[
{"Front": "あっ", "Back": "Ah!,Oh!", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "愛", "Back": "love", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "挨拶", "Back": "greeting,salutation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "愛情", "Back": "love,affection", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "合図", "Back": "sign,signal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アイスクリーム", "Back": "ice cream", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "愛する", "Back": "to love", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "相手", "Back": "companion,partner,company", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あいにく", "Back": "unfortunately,Sorry, but....", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アイロン", "Back": "(electric) iron", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アウト", "Back": "out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "明かり", "Back": "lamplight,light (in general),brightness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "空き", "Back": "room,time to spare,emptiness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "明らか", "Back": "obvious,evident,clear", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "諦める", "Back": "to give up,to abandon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "飽きる", "Back": "to get tired of,to lose interest in,to have enough", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "握手", "Back": "handshake", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悪魔", "Back": "devil,demon,evil spirit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "明ける", "Back": "to dawn,to become daylight", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あした", "Back": "tomorrow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "預ける", "Back": "to give into custody,to entrust,to deposit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "汗", "Back": "sweat,perspiration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "与える", "Back": "to give,to present,to award", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暖かい", "Back": "warm,mild", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "辺り", "Back": "vicinity,nearby", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "当たる", "Back": "to be hit,to be successful,to be equivalent to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あちこち", "Back": "here and there", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "扱う", "Back": "to handle,to deal with,to treat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "集まり", "Back": "gathering,meeting,assembly,collection", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "当てる", "Back": "to hit,to apply a patch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "跡", "Back": "(1) trace,tracks,mark,sign,(2) remains,ruins,(3) scar", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あと", "Back": "(1) trace,tracks,(2) remains,ruins,(3) scar", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "穴", "Back": "hole", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "浴びる", "Back": "to bathe,to bask in the sun,to shower", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "油", "Back": "oil", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "余り", "Back": "not very (used as adverb),not much", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誤り", "Back": "error", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "粗", "Back": "defect,flaw,blemish,weak point", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嵐", "Back": "storm,tempest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "新た", "Back": "new,fresh,novel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あらゆる", "Back": "all,every", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "表す", "Back": "to express,to show,to reveal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "現す", "Back": "to show,to indicate,to display", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "現れ", "Back": "embodiment,materialization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "現れる", "Back": "(1) to appear,to come in sight,to become visible,(2) to express oneself", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ありがとう", "Back": "(conj,exp,int) Thank you", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "有る", "Back": "to be,to have", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "或", "Back": "a certain...,some...", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あるいは", "Back": "or,possibly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アルバム", "Back": "album", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "泡", "Back": "bubble,foam,froth,head on beer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "合わせる", "Back": "to join together,to be opposite,to face,to unite", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "哀れ", "Back": "helpless,pity,sorrow,grief", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "案", "Back": "plan,suffix meaning draft", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暗記", "Back": "memorization,learning by heart", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "安定", "Back": "stability,equilibrium", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "案内", "Back": "information,guidance,leading", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あんなに", "Back": "to that extent,to that degree", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あんまり", "Back": "not very,not much,remainder,rest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "胃", "Back": "stomach", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いい", "Back": "good", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "よい", "Back": "good,nice,pleasant,ok", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いえ", "Back": "TODO same as いいえ?", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "委員", "Back": "committee member", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "言う", "Back": "to say", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "意外", "Back": "unexpected,surprising", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "行き", "Back": "going", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "息", "Back": "breath,tone", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勢い", "Back": "force,vigor,energy,spirit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生き物", "Back": "living thing,animal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幾つ", "Back": "how many?,how old?", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幾ら", "Back": "how much?,how many?", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いけない", "Back": "must not do,bad,wrong,not good", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "医師", "Back": "doctor,physician", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "意思", "Back": "intention,purpose", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "意志", "Back": "will,volition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "維持", "Back": "maintenance,preservation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "意識", "Back": "consciousness,senses", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "異常", "Back": "strangeness,abnormality,disorder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "椅子", "Back": "chair", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "泉", "Back": "spring,fountain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いずれ", "Back": "where,which,who", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "以前", "Back": "ago,since,before,previous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "板", "Back": "board,plank", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "偉大", "Back": "greatness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "抱く", "Back": "(sl) to embrace,to hug,to harbour,to entertain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いたずら", "Back": "tease,prank,trick,practical joke", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いただきます", "Back": "expression of gratitude before meals", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "頂く", "Back": "to receive,to take food or drink (hum)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "痛み", "Back": "pain,ache,sore,grief,distress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "至る", "Back": "to come,to arrive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いち", "Back": "market,fair", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "位置", "Back": "place,situation,position,location", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一時", "Back": "moment,time", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一度に", "Back": "all at once", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "市場", "Back": "(the) market (as a concept)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一番", "Back": "best,first,number one", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いつか", "Back": "sometime,someday,one day", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一家", "Back": "a house,a home,a family,a household", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一種", "Back": "a species,a kind,a variety", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一瞬", "Back": "a moment,an instant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一生", "Back": "whole life,a lifetime,all through life", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一層", "Back": "much more,still more,all the more", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一体", "Back": "(1) one object,one body,(2) what on earth?,really?,(3) generally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一致", "Back": "(1) coincidence,agreement,(2) conformity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いつでも", "Back": "(at) any time,always,at all times,never (neg)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一般", "Back": "general,liberal,universal,ordinary,average", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一方", "Back": "(1) on the other hand,(2) meanwhile,(3) only,simple,in turn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いつまでも", "Back": "forever,for good,eternally,as long as one likes,indefinitely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いつも", "Back": "always,usually,every time,never (with neg. verb)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "移動", "Back": "removal,migration,movement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "従兄弟", "Back": "cousin (male)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "稲", "Back": "rice-plant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "居眠り", "Back": "dozing,nodding off", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "命", "Back": "command,decree,life,destiny", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "違反", "Back": "violation (of law),transgression,infringement,breach", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "衣服", "Back": "clothes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "居間", "Back": "living room (western style)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "今に", "Back": "before long,even now", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "今にも", "Back": "at any time,soon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "否", "Back": "no,the noes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "以来", "Back": "since,henceforth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "依頼", "Back": "(1) request,commission,dispatch,(2) dependence,trust", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いらいら", "Back": "getting nervous,irritation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いらっしゃい", "Back": "welcome", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "医療", "Back": "medical care,medical treatment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "岩", "Back": "rock,crag", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "祝い", "Back": "celebration,festival", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "祝う", "Back": "to congratulate,to celebrate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "言わば", "Back": "so to speak", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いわゆる", "Back": "the so-called,so to speak", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "インク", "Back": "ink", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "印刷", "Back": "printing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "印象", "Back": "impression", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引退", "Back": "retire", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引用", "Back": "quotation,citation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ウイスキー", "Back": "whisky", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上", "Back": "upper,outer,surface", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "魚", "Back": "fish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "うがい", "Back": "gargle,rinse mouth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "伺う", "Back": "(hon) to visit,to ask,to inquire", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "受け取る", "Back": "to receive,to get,to accept,to take", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "動かす", "Back": "to move,to shift", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "兎", "Back": "rabbit,hare,cony", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "牛", "Back": "cattle,cow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "失う", "Back": "to lose,to part with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "後", "Back": "afterwards,since then,in the future", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嘘", "Back": "lie,falsehood,incorrect fact,inappropriate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "疑う", "Back": "to doubt,to distrust,to be suspicious of,to suspect", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "内", "Back": "inside", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宇宙", "Back": "universe,cosmos,space", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "撃つ", "Back": "to attack,to defeat,to destroy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "移す", "Back": "to remove,to transfer,to infect", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "訴える", "Back": "to sue (a person),to resort to,to appeal to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "うなる", "Back": "to groan,to moan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "奪う", "Back": "to snatch away", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "馬", "Back": "(1) horse,(2) promoted bishop (shogi)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "うまい", "Back": "delicious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生まれ", "Back": "birth,birth-place", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "梅", "Back": "plum,plum-tree,lowest (of a three-tier ranking system)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "裏切る", "Back": "to betray,to turn traitor to,to double-cross", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "うるさい", "Back": "noisy,loud,fussy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嬉しい", "Back": "happy,glad,pleasant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "売れる", "Back": "to be sold", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "噂", "Back": "rumour,report,gossip,common talk", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "うん", "Back": "fortune,luck", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "運", "Back": "fortune,luck", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "運転", "Back": "operation,motion,driving", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "運動", "Back": "motion,exercise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "柄", "Back": "handle,grip", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "永遠", "Back": "eternity,perpetuity,immortality,permanence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "永久", "Back": "eternity,perpetuity,immortality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "影響", "Back": "influence,effect", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "営業", "Back": "business,trade,management", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "衛星", "Back": "satellite", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "栄養", "Back": "nutrition,nourishment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "笑顔", "Back": "smiling face", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "描く", "Back": "to draw,to paint,to sketch,to depict,to describe", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "餌", "Back": "feed,bait", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "エネルギー", "Back": "(n) energy (de: Energie)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "得る", "Back": "to get,to gain,to win", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "円", "Back": "circle,money", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "延期", "Back": "postponement,adjournment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "演技", "Back": "acting,performance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "援助", "Back": "assistance,aid,support", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "エンジン", "Back": "engine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "演説", "Back": "speech,address", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "演奏", "Back": "musical performance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遠慮", "Back": "diffidence,restraint,reserve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "御", "Back": "honourable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "老い", "Back": "old age,old person,the old,the aged", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "追い付く", "Back": "to overtake,to catch up (with)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "王", "Back": "king,ruler,sovereign,monarch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "追う", "Back": "to chase,to run after", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "王様", "Back": "king", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "王子", "Back": "prince", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "応じる", "Back": "to respond,to satisfy,to accept,to comply with,to apply for", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "横断", "Back": "crossing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "終える", "Back": "to finish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大いに", "Back": "very,much,greatly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "覆う", "Back": "to cover,to hide,to conceal,to wrap,to disguise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "オーバー", "Back": "(1) overcoat,(2) over", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大家", "Back": "rich family,distinguished family", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "丘", "Back": "hill,height,knoll,rising ground", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "沖", "Back": "open sea", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "奥", "Back": "interior,inner part", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "贈る", "Back": "to send,to give to,to award to,to confer on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "起こる", "Back": "to occur,to happen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幼い", "Back": "very young,childish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "収める", "Back": "to obtain,to reap,to pay,to supply,to accept", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おじいさん", "Back": "grandfather,male senior-citizen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おしゃべり", "Back": "chattering,talk,idle talk", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "汚染", "Back": "pollution,contamination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おそらく", "Back": "perhaps", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恐れる", "Back": "to fear,to be afraid of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恐ろしい", "Back": "terrible,dreadful", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お互い", "Back": "mutual,reciprocal,each other", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "穏やか", "Back": "calm,gentle,quiet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "男の人", "Back": "man", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "劣る", "Back": "to fall behind,to be inferior to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お腹", "Back": "stomach", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鬼", "Back": "ogre,demon,it (i.e., in a game of tag)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "帯", "Back": "band (e.g. conduction, valence)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お昼", "Back": "lunch,noon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "オフィス", "Back": "office", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "溺れる", "Back": "to be drowned,to indulge in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おまえ", "Back": "(fam) you (sing),presence (of a high personage)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おめでとう", "Back": "Congratulations!,an auspicious occasion!", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お目に掛かる", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "思い出", "Back": "memories,recollections,reminiscence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "主に", "Back": "mainly,primarily", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "思わず", "Back": "unintentional,spontaneous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おや", "Back": "parents", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "泳ぎ", "Back": "swimming", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "およそ", "Back": "about,roughly,as a rule,approximately", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "及ぼす", "Back": "to exert,to cause,to exercise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "居る", "Back": "to be (animate),to be,to exist", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下す", "Back": "to lower,to let go down", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "降ろす", "Back": "to take down,to launch,to drop", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "終", "Back": "the end", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "音", "Back": "sound,note", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恩", "Back": "favour,obligation,debt of gratitude", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "温暖", "Back": "warmth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "温度", "Back": "temperature", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "可", "Back": "passable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "課", "Back": "counter for chapters (of a book)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "カー", "Back": "car", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "カード", "Back": "card,curd", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "会", "Back": "meeting,assembly,party,association,club", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "回", "Back": "counter for occurrences", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "害", "Back": "injury,harm,evil influence,damage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "会員", "Back": "member,the membership", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "絵画", "Back": "picture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "海外", "Back": "foreign,abroad,overseas", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "会計", "Back": "account,finance,accountant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "解決", "Back": "settlement,solution,resolution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "会合", "Back": "meeting,assembly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "外交", "Back": "diplomacy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "開始", "Back": "start,commencement,beginning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "解釈", "Back": "explanation,interpretation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "外出", "Back": "outing,going out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "改善", "Back": "betterment,improvement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "快適", "Back": "pleasant,agreeable,comfortable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "回復", "Back": "recovery (from illness),improvement,rehabilitation,restoration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "飼う", "Back": "to keep,to raise,to feed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "替える", "Back": "to exchange,to interchange,to substitute,to replace", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "換える", "Back": "to exchange,to interchange,to substitute,to replace", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "香り", "Back": "aroma,fragrance,scent,smell", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "画家", "Back": "painter,artist", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "抱える", "Back": "to hold or carry under or in the arms", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "価格", "Back": "price,value,cost", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "化学", "Back": "chemistry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "輝く", "Back": "to shine,to glitter,to sparkle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "係", "Back": "official,duty,person in charge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "掛かる", "Back": "to take (e.g. time, money, etc),to hang", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "罹る", "Back": "to suffer from", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鍵", "Back": "key", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "限る", "Back": "to restrict,to limit,to confine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "家具", "Back": "furniture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "学", "Back": "learning,scholarship,erudition,knowledge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "額", "Back": "forehead,brow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "覚悟", "Back": "resolution,resignation,readiness,preparedness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "確実", "Back": "certainty,reliability,soundness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "学者", "Back": "scholar", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "学習", "Back": "study,learning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "隠す", "Back": "to hide,to conceal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "拡大", "Back": "magnification,enlargement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "確認", "Back": "affirmation,confirmation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "学問", "Back": "scholarship,study,learning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "隠れる", "Back": "to hide,to be hidden,to conceal oneself,to disappear", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "影", "Back": "shade,shadow,other side", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "陰", "Back": "shade,shadow,other side", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "欠ける", "Back": "to be lacking", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "加減", "Back": "addition and subtraction,allowance for", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "過去", "Back": "the past,bygone days,the previous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "籠", "Back": "basket,cage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "囲む", "Back": "to surround,to encircle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "火災", "Back": "conflagration,fire", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貸し", "Back": "loan,lending", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "菓子", "Back": "pastry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "家事", "Back": "housework,domestic chores", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "賢い", "Back": "wise,clever,smart", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "歌手", "Back": "singer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "数", "Back": "number,figure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "稼ぐ", "Back": "to earn income,to labor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "数える", "Back": "to count", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "型", "Back": "mold,model,style,shape,data-type", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "肩", "Back": "shoulder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "硬い", "Back": "solid,hard (esp. metal, stone),unpolished writing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "方々", "Back": "persons,this and that,here and there,everywhere", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "刀", "Back": "sword,saber,knife,engraving tool", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "語る", "Back": "to talk,to tell,to recite", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勝ち", "Back": "win,victory", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "価値", "Back": "value,worth,merit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "がっかり", "Back": "feel disappointed,be dejected,lose heart", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "活気", "Back": "energy,liveliness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "学期", "Back": "term (school)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "格好", "Back": "shape,form,posture,suitability", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "活動", "Back": "action,activity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "活用", "Back": "conjugation,practical use", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悲しむ", "Back": "to be sad,to mourn for,to regret", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "必ずしも", "Back": "(not) always,(not) necessarily,(not) all,(not) entirely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "かなり", "Back": "considerably,fairly,quite", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "金", "Back": "(1) gold,(2) gold general (shogi) (abbr)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "金持ち", "Back": "rich man", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "可能", "Back": "possible,practicable,feasible", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "株", "Back": "share,stock,stump (of tree)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "被る", "Back": "to suffer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "構う", "Back": "to mind,to care about,to be concerned about", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "我慢", "Back": "patience,endurance,perseverance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "神", "Back": "god", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雷", "Back": "thunder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "髪の毛", "Back": "hair (head)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "科目", "Back": "(school) subject,curriculum,course", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "かもしれない", "Back": "may,might,perhaps,may be,possibly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "火曜", "Back": "(abbr) Tuesday", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "空", "Back": "sky", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "刈る", "Back": "to cut (hair),to mow (grass),to harvest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "彼等", "Back": "they (usually male)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "川", "Back": "river", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "河", "Back": "river,stream", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "皮", "Back": "skin,hide,leather,fur,pelt,bark,shell", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "革", "Back": "leather", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "かわいそう", "Back": "poor,pitiable,pathetic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "かわいらしい", "Back": "lovely,sweet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "缶", "Back": "can,tin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勘", "Back": "perception,intuition,the sixth sense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "考え", "Back": "thinking,thought,ideas,intention", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "感覚", "Back": "sense,sensation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "観客", "Back": "audience,spectator(s)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "環境", "Back": "environment,circumstance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "歓迎", "Back": "welcome,reception", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "観光", "Back": "sightseeing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "感じ", "Back": "feeling,sense,impression", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "観察", "Back": "observation,survey", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "感謝", "Back": "thanks,gratitude", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "患者", "Back": "a patient", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勘定", "Back": "calculation,counting,consideration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "感情", "Back": "emotion(s),feeling(s),sentiment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "感じる", "Back": "to feel,to sense,to experience", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "感心", "Back": "admiration,Well done!", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "関心", "Back": "concern,interest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "関する", "Back": "to concern,to be related", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "完成", "Back": "(1) complete,completion,(2) perfection,accomplishment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "完全", "Back": "perfection,completeness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "感動", "Back": "being deeply moved,excitement,impression,deep emotion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "監督", "Back": "supervision,control,superintendence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "管理", "Back": "control,management (e.g. of a business)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "完了", "Back": "completion,conclusion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "関連", "Back": "relation,connection,relevance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "議員", "Back": "member of the Diet, congress or parliament", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "記憶", "Back": "memory,recollection,remembrance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気温", "Back": "temperature", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "機械", "Back": "machine,mechanism", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "議会", "Back": "Diet,congress,parliament", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "期間", "Back": "period,term", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "機関", "Back": "organ,mechanism,facility,engine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "企業", "Back": "enterprise,undertaking", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "効く", "Back": "to be effective", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "機嫌", "Back": "humour,temper,mood", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気候", "Back": "climate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "岸", "Back": "bank,coast,shore", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生地", "Back": "birthplace", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "記事", "Back": "article,news story,report,account", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "技師", "Back": "engineer,technician", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "記者", "Back": "reporter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "傷", "Back": "wound,injury,hurt,cut", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "期待", "Back": "expectation,anticipation,hope", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "帰宅", "Back": "returning home", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貴重", "Back": "precious,valuable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "議長", "Back": "chairman", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "きちんと", "Back": "precisely,accurately", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "きつい", "Back": "tight,close,intense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気付く", "Back": "to notice,to recognize,to become aware of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気に入る", "Back": "to be pleased with,to suit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "記入", "Back": "entry,filling in of forms", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "記念", "Back": "commemoration,memory", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "機能", "Back": "function,faculty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気の毒", "Back": "pitiful,a pity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寄付", "Back": "contribution,donation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "希望", "Back": "hope,wish,aspiration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "基本", "Back": "foundation,basis,standard", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "決まり", "Back": "settlement,conclusion,regulation,rule", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気味", "Back": "-like,-looking,-looked", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "奇妙", "Back": "strange,queer,curious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "義務", "Back": "duty,obligation,responsibility", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "疑問", "Back": "question,problem,doubt,guess", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "逆", "Back": "reverse,opposite", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "キャプテン", "Back": "captain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "キャンプ", "Back": "camp", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "九", "Back": "nine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "旧", "Back": "ex-", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "級", "Back": "class, grade, rank,school class, grade", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "球", "Back": "globe,sphere,ball", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "休暇", "Back": "holiday,day off,furlough", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "休憩", "Back": "rest,break,recess,intermission", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "急激", "Back": "sudden,precipitous,radical", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "吸収", "Back": "absorption,suction,attraction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "救助", "Back": "relief,aid,rescue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "急速", "Back": "rapid (e.g. progress)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "急に", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "給料", "Back": "salary,wages", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "器用", "Back": "skillful,handy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "教科書", "Back": "text book", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "競技", "Back": "game,match,contest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "行儀", "Back": "manners", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "供給", "Back": "supply,provision", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "教師", "Back": "teacher (classroom)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "教授", "Back": "teaching,instruction,professor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "強調", "Back": "emphasis,stress,stressed point", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "共通", "Back": "commonness,community", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "共同", "Back": "cooperation,association,collaboration,joint", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恐怖", "Back": "be afraid,dread,dismay,terror", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "協力", "Back": "cooperation,collaboration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "強力", "Back": "herculean strength,mountain carrier-guide", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "許可", "Back": "permission,approval", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "局", "Back": "court lady,lady in waiting", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "巨大", "Back": "huge,gigantic,enormous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嫌う", "Back": "to hate,to dislike,to loathe", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "霧", "Back": "fog,mist", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "切れ", "Back": "cloth,piece,cut,chop", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "切れる", "Back": "(1) to cut well,to be sharp,(2) to break (off)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "キロ", "Back": "(abbr) kilo-,kilogram,kilometre,10^3", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "記録", "Back": "record,minutes,document", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "議論", "Back": "argument,discussion,dispute", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "銀", "Back": "(1) silver,silver coin,silver paint", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "禁煙", "Back": "No Smoking!", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "金額", "Back": "amount of money", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "金庫", "Back": "safe,vault,treasury,provider of funds", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "禁止", "Back": "prohibition,ban", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "金銭", "Back": "money,cash", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "金属", "Back": "metal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "近代", "Back": "present day", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "緊張", "Back": "tension,mental strain,nervousness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "筋肉", "Back": "muscle,sinew", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "金融", "Back": "monetary circulation,credit situation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "金曜", "Back": "(abbr) Friday", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "句", "Back": "sentence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "食う", "Back": "(male) (vulg) to eat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "偶然", "Back": "(by) chance,unexpectedly,suddenly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "臭い", "Back": "odour,scent,smell,stench", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鎖", "Back": "chain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "腐る", "Back": "to rot,to go bad", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "癖", "Back": "a habit (often a bad habit),peculiarity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "管", "Back": "pipe,tube", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "具体", "Back": "concrete,tangible,material", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下さる", "Back": "(hon) to give,to confer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下り", "Back": "down-train (going away from Tokyo)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "苦痛", "Back": "pain,agony", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぐっすり", "Back": "sound asleep,fast asleep", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "区別", "Back": "distinction,differentiation,classification", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "組", "Back": "class,group,team,set", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "組合", "Back": "association,union", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "組む", "Back": "to put together", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "曇", "Back": "cloudiness,cloudy weather,shadow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "位", "Back": "grade,rank,about", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暮らし", "Back": "living,livelihood,subsistence,circumstances", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "クラシック", "Back": "classic(s)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暮らす", "Back": "to live,to get along", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "グラス", "Back": "(1) glass,(2) grass", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "グランド", "Back": "gland,grand,(electrical) ground", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "クリーム", "Back": "cream", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "繰り返す", "Back": "to repeat,to do something over again", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "クリスマス", "Back": "Christmas", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "狂う", "Back": "to go mad,to get out of order", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "グループ", "Back": "group", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "苦しい", "Back": "painful,difficult", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "苦しむ", "Back": "to suffer,to groan,to be worried", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暮れ", "Back": "year end,sunset,nightfall,end", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "苦労", "Back": "troubles,hardships", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "加える", "Back": "to append,to sum up,to add (up)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "詳しい", "Back": "knowing very well,detailed,full,accurate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "加わる", "Back": "to join in,to accede to,to increase,to gain in (influence)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "訓", "Back": "native Japanese reading of a Chinese character", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軍", "Back": "army,force,troops", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軍隊", "Back": "army,troops", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "訓練", "Back": "practice,training", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下", "Back": "under,below,beneath", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "計", "Back": "plan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "敬意", "Back": "respect,honour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "経営", "Back": "management,administration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "計画", "Back": "plan,project,schedule,scheme,program", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "景気", "Back": "condition,state,business (condition)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "経験", "Back": "experience", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "傾向", "Back": "tendency,trend,inclination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "警告", "Back": "warning,advice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "計算", "Back": "calculation,reckoning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "掲示", "Back": "notice,bulletin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "刑事", "Back": "criminal case,(police) detective", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "芸術", "Back": "(fine) art,the arts", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "契約", "Back": "contract,compact,agreement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "経由", "Back": "go by the way,via", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ケース", "Back": "case", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ゲーム", "Back": "game", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "怪我", "Back": "injury (to animate object),hurt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "劇", "Back": "drama,play", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "劇場", "Back": "theatre,playhouse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "化粧", "Back": "make-up (cosmetic)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "けち", "Back": "stinginess,miser,miserliness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "結果", "Back": "result,consequence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "欠陥", "Back": "defect,fault,deficiency", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "結局", "Back": "after all,eventually", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "決心", "Back": "determination,resolution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "欠席", "Back": "absence,non-attendance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "決定", "Back": "decision,determination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "欠点", "Back": "faults,defect,weakness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "月曜", "Back": "Monday", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "結論", "Back": "conclusion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "煙", "Back": "smoke,fumes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "券", "Back": "ticket,coupon,bond,certificate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "県", "Back": "prefecture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軒", "Back": "eaves", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "喧嘩", "Back": "quarrel,(drunken) brawl,failure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見解", "Back": "opinion,point of view", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "限界", "Back": "limit,bound", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "現金", "Back": "cash,ready money,mercenary,self-interested", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "言語", "Back": "language", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "健康", "Back": "health,sound,wholesome", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "検査", "Back": "inspection (e.g. customs, factory),examination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "現在", "Back": "present,up to now,nowadays,modern times,current", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "現実", "Back": "reality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "現象", "Back": "phenomenon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "現状", "Back": "present condition,existing state,status quo", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "建設", "Back": "construction,establishment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "現代", "Back": "nowadays,modern times,present-day", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "建築", "Back": "construction,architecture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見当", "Back": "be found,aim,estimate,guess,approx", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "検討", "Back": "consideration,examination,investigation,study,scrutiny", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "現場", "Back": "actual spot,scene,scene of the crime", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "憲法", "Back": "constitution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "権利", "Back": "right,privilege", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "語", "Back": "language,word", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恋", "Back": "love,tender passion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "濃い", "Back": "thick (as of color, liquid),dense,strong", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恋人", "Back": "lover,sweetheart", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幸運", "Back": "good luck,fortune", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "講演", "Back": "lecture,address", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "効果", "Back": "effect,effectiveness,efficacy,result", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "硬貨", "Back": "coin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "高価", "Back": "high price", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "豪華", "Back": "wonderful,gorgeous,splendor,pomp,extravagance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "合格", "Back": "success,passing (e.g. exam),eligibility", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "交換", "Back": "exchange,interchange,reciprocity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "航空", "Back": "aviation,flying", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "光景", "Back": "scene,spectacle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "合計", "Back": "sum total,total amount", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "攻撃", "Back": "attack,strike,offensive,criticism,censure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貢献", "Back": "contribution,services", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "広告", "Back": "advertisement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "交際", "Back": "company,friendship,association,society,acquaintance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "後者", "Back": "the latter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "工場", "Back": "factory,plant,mill,workshop", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "構成", "Back": "organization,composition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "高速", "Back": "high speed,high gear", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "行動", "Back": "action,conduct,behaviour,mobilization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "強盗", "Back": "robbery,burglary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幸福", "Back": "happiness,blessedness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "公平", "Back": "fairness,impartial,justice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "候補", "Back": "candidacy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "考慮", "Back": "consideration,taking into account", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "越える", "Back": "to exceed,to cross over,to cross", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コーチ", "Back": "coach", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コード", "Back": "code,cord,chord", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "氷", "Back": "ice,hail", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "凍る", "Back": "to freeze,to be frozen over,to congeal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ゴール", "Back": "goal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誤解", "Back": "misunderstanding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "語学", "Back": "language study", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "呼吸", "Back": "breath,respiration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "故郷", "Back": "home town,birthplace,old village,historic village", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "極", "Back": "quite,very", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "国語", "Back": "national language", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "黒板", "Back": "blackboard", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "克服", "Back": "subjugation,conquest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "国民", "Back": "national,people,citizen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "穀物", "Back": "grain,cereal,corn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ここ", "Back": "here", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "腰", "Back": "hip", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "故障", "Back": "break-down,failure,accident,out of order", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "個人", "Back": "individual,private person,personal,private", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "越す", "Back": "to go over (e.g. with audience)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "国家", "Back": "state,country,nation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "国会", "Back": "National Diet,parliament,congress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "国境", "Back": "national or state border", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "骨折", "Back": "bone fracture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "小包", "Back": "parcel,package", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "事", "Back": "thing,matter,fact,circumstances", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "異なる", "Back": "to differ,to vary,to disagree", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "諺", "Back": "proverb,maxim", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "断る", "Back": "to refuse,to decline,to dismiss", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "粉", "Back": "flour,meal,powder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "この", "Back": "this", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "好み", "Back": "liking,taste,choice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "好む", "Back": "to like,to prefer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コピー", "Back": "(1) a (photo)copy,(2) blurb on a book jacket", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "塵", "Back": "dust,dirt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "小麦", "Back": "wheat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ごめんなさい", "Back": "I beg your pardon,excuse me", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "小屋", "Back": "hut,cabin,shed,(animal) pen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "これら", "Back": "these", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "頃", "Back": "time,about,toward,approximately (time)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "殺す", "Back": "to kill", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "転ぶ", "Back": "to fall down,to fall over", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "今回", "Back": "now,this time,lately", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "今後", "Back": "from now on,hereafter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "混雑", "Back": "confusion,congestion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "こんなに", "Back": "so,like this,in this way", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "困難", "Back": "difficulty,distress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "今日", "Back": "today,this day", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "こんにちは", "Back": "hello,good day (daytime greeting, id)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コンピューター", "Back": "computer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "婚約", "Back": "engagement,betrothal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "混乱", "Back": "disorder,chaos,confusion,mayhem", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "差", "Back": "difference,variation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "サービス", "Back": "(1) service,support system,(2) goods or services without charge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "際", "Back": "on the occasion of,circumstances", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "最高", "Back": "highest,supreme,the most", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "財産", "Back": "property,fortune,assets", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "最終", "Back": "last,final,closing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "最中", "Back": "in the middle of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "最低", "Back": "least,lowest,worst", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "才能", "Back": "talent,ability", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "裁判", "Back": "trial,judgement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "材料", "Back": "ingredients,material", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幸い", "Back": "happiness,blessedness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "サイン", "Back": "(1) autograph,(2) sign,(3) sine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "境", "Back": "border,boundary,mental state", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "逆らう", "Back": "to go against,to oppose,to disobey,to defy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "盛り", "Back": "helping,serving", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "作業", "Back": "work,operation,manufacturing,fatigue duty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "昨", "Back": "last (year),yesterday", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "作品", "Back": "work,opus,performance,production", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "作物", "Back": "produce (e.g. agricultural),crops", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "桜", "Back": "cherry blossom,cherry tree", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "酒", "Back": "alcohol,sake", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "叫ぶ", "Back": "to shout,to cry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "避ける", "Back": "(1) to avoid (physical contact ),(2) to ward off,to avert", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "支える", "Back": "to be blocked,to choke,to be obstructed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "指す", "Back": "to point,to put up umbrella,to play", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "座席", "Back": "seat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誘う", "Back": "(1) to invite,to ask,(2) to tempt,to lure,to induce", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "札", "Back": "(1) token,label,(2) ticket,(3) charm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "作家", "Back": "author,writer,novelist,artist", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "作曲", "Back": "composition,setting (of music)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ざっと", "Back": "roughly,in round numbers", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "さっぱり", "Back": "feeling refreshed,feeling relieved,neat,trimmed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "さて", "Back": "well,now,then", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "砂漠", "Back": "desert", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "差別", "Back": "discrimination,distinction,differentiation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "作法", "Back": "manners,etiquette,propriety", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "様々", "Back": "varied,various", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "覚ます", "Back": "to awaken", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "覚める", "Back": "to wake,to wake up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "左右", "Back": "(1) left and right,(2) influence,control,domination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "皿", "Back": "plate,dish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "更に", "Back": "furthermore,again,after all,more and more,moreover", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "去る", "Back": "to leave,to go away", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "猿", "Back": "monkey", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "騒ぎ", "Back": "uproar,disturbance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "参加", "Back": "participation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "参考", "Back": "reference,consultation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "賛成", "Back": "approval,agreement,support,favour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "酸素", "Back": "oxygen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "散歩", "Back": "walk,stroll", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "四", "Back": "four", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "氏", "Back": "family name,lineage,birth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "詩", "Back": "poem,verse of poetry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幸せ", "Back": "happiness,good fortune,luck,blessing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ジーンズ", "Back": "jeans", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ジェット機", "Back": "jet aeroplane", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "直に", "Back": "immediately,readily,directly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しかも", "Back": "moreover,furthermore,nevertheless,and yet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "叱る", "Back": "to scold", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "式", "Back": "equation,formula,ceremony", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "直", "Back": "earnestly,immediately,exactly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "時期", "Back": "time,season,period", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "支給", "Back": "payment,allowance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しきりに", "Back": "frequently,repeatedly,incessantly,eagerly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "刺激", "Back": "stimulus,impetus,incentive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "資源", "Back": "resources", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "事件", "Back": "event,affair,incident", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "時刻", "Back": "instant,time,moment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自殺", "Back": "suicide", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "事実", "Back": "fact,truth,reality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "支出", "Back": "expenditure,expenses", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "事情", "Back": "circumstances,consideration,conditions,situation,reasons", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "詩人", "Back": "poet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自身", "Back": "by oneself,personally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "沈む", "Back": "to sink,to feel depressed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自然", "Back": "nature,spontaneous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "思想", "Back": "thought,idea", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "舌", "Back": "tongue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "次第", "Back": "(1) order,precedence,(2) circumstances,(3) immediate(ly)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "事態", "Back": "situation,present state of affairs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "従う", "Back": "to abide (by the rules),to obey,to follow,to accompany", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "したがって", "Back": "therefore,consequently,in accordance with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "支度", "Back": "preparation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "親しい", "Back": "intimate,close (e.g. friend)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "七", "Back": "seven", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "質", "Back": "quality,nature (of person)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "失業", "Back": "unemployment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実験", "Back": "experiment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実現", "Back": "implementation,materialization,realization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実行", "Back": "practice,performance,execution (e.g. program),realization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実際", "Back": "practical,actual condition,status quo", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実施", "Back": "enforcement,enact,put into practice,carry out,operation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "じっと", "Back": "fixedly,firmly,patiently,quietly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実に", "Back": "indeed,truly,surely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実は", "Back": "as a matter of fact,by the way", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "失望", "Back": "disappointment,despair", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "支店", "Back": "branch store (office)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "指導", "Back": "leadership,guidance,coaching", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自動", "Back": "automatic,self-motion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "品", "Back": "thing,article,goods,dignity,article (goods),counter for meal courses", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "支配", "Back": "rule,control,direction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "芝居", "Back": "play,drama", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しばしば", "Back": "often,again and again,frequently", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "芝生", "Back": "lawn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "支払", "Back": "payment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "支払う", "Back": "to pay", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "死亡", "Back": "death,mortality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "資本", "Back": "funds,capital", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しまい", "Back": "sisters", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "姉妹", "Back": "sisters", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しまう", "Back": "to finish,to close,to do something completely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しまった", "Back": "Damn it!", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自慢", "Back": "pride,boast", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "事務", "Back": "business,office work", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "示す", "Back": "to denote,to show,to point out,to indicate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "占める", "Back": "(1) to comprise,to account for,to make up (of),(2) to hold,to occupy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "霜", "Back": "frost", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "じゃあ", "Back": "well,well then", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "借金", "Back": "debt,loan,liabilities", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しゃべる", "Back": "to talk,to chat,to chatter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "邪魔", "Back": "hindrance,intrusion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "週", "Back": "week", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "州", "Back": "sandbank", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "十", "Back": "10,ten", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "銃", "Back": "gun", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "周囲", "Back": "surroundings,circumference,environs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "収穫", "Back": "harvest,crop,ingathering", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "週間", "Back": "week,weekly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宗教", "Back": "religion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重視", "Back": "importance,stress,serious consideration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "就職", "Back": "finding employment,inauguration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ジュース", "Back": "juice,soft drink,deuce", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "修正", "Back": "amendment,correction,revision,modification", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "渋滞", "Back": "congestion (e.g. traffic),delay,stagnation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重大", "Back": "serious,important,grave,weighty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "住宅", "Back": "resident,housing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "集団", "Back": "group,mass", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "集中", "Back": "concentration,focusing the mind", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "収入", "Back": "income,receipts,revenue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "住民", "Back": "citizens,inhabitants,residents,population", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重要", "Back": "important,momentous,essential,principal,major", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "修理", "Back": "repairing,mending", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "主義", "Back": "doctrine,rule,principle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宿泊", "Back": "lodging", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手術", "Back": "surgical operation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "首相", "Back": "Prime Minister", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手段", "Back": "means,way,measure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "主張", "Back": "claim,request,insistence,assertion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出身", "Back": "graduate from,come from", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出席", "Back": "attendance,presence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出発", "Back": "departure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出版", "Back": "publication", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "首都", "Back": "capital city", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "主婦", "Back": "housewife,mistress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "主要", "Back": "chief,main,principal,major", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "需要", "Back": "demand,request", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "種類", "Back": "variety,kind,type", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "順", "Back": "order,turn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "瞬間", "Back": "moment,second,instant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "順調", "Back": "favourable,doing well,O.K.,all right", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "順番", "Back": "turn (in line),order of things", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "準備", "Back": "preparation,arrangements,provision,reserve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "使用", "Back": "use,application,employment,utilization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "小", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "章", "Back": "(1) chapter,section,(2) medal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "賞", "Back": "prize,award", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "障害", "Back": "obstacle,impediment (fault),damage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "奨学金", "Back": "scholarship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乗客", "Back": "passenger", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上京", "Back": "proceeding to the capital (Tokyo)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "状況", "Back": "state of affairs,situation,circumstances", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "条件", "Back": "conditions,terms", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "正午", "Back": "noon,mid-day", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "正直", "Back": "honesty,integrity,frankness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "常識", "Back": "common sense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "少女", "Back": "daughter,young lady,virgin,maiden,little girl", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "少々", "Back": "just a minute,small quantity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "症状", "Back": "symptoms,condition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生じる", "Back": "to produce,to yield,to result from,to arise,to be generated", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "招待", "Back": "invitation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "状態", "Back": "condition,situation,circumstances,state", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上達", "Back": "improvement,advance,progress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "冗談", "Back": "jest,joke", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "承知", "Back": "consent,acceptance,assent,admitting", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上等", "Back": "superiority,first class,very good", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "衝突", "Back": "collision,conflict", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "商人", "Back": "trader,shopkeeper,merchant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "承認", "Back": "recognition,acknowledgement,approval,consent,agreement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "少年", "Back": "boys,juveniles", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "商売", "Back": "trade,business,commerce,transaction,occupation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "消費", "Back": "consumption,expenditure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "商品", "Back": "commodity,article of commerce,goods,stock,merchandise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "消防", "Back": "fire fighting,fire department", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "情報", "Back": "information,(military) intelligence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "証明", "Back": "proof,verification", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "女王", "Back": "queen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "職", "Back": "employment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "職業", "Back": "occupation,business", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "食事", "Back": "meal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "食卓", "Back": "dining table", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "食品", "Back": "commodity,foodstuff", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "植物", "Back": "plant,vegetation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "食物", "Back": "food,foodstuff", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "食欲", "Back": "appetite (for food)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "食料", "Back": "food", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "食糧", "Back": "provisions,rations", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "書斎", "Back": "study", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "女子", "Back": "woman,girl", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "助手", "Back": "helper,helpmeet,assistant,tutor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "徐々に", "Back": "slowly,little by little,gradually,steadily,quietly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "署名", "Back": "signature", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "書物", "Back": "books", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "女優", "Back": "actress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "処理", "Back": "processing,dealing with,treatment,disposition,disposal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "書類", "Back": "documents,official papers", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "知らせ", "Back": "notice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "尻", "Back": "buttocks,bottom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "印", "Back": "(1) mark,(2) symbol,(3) evidence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "城", "Back": "castle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "進学", "Back": "going on to university", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "神経", "Back": "nerve,sensitivity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真剣", "Back": "seriousness,earnestness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "信仰", "Back": "(religious) faith,belief,creed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "信号", "Back": "traffic lights,signal,semaphore", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人工", "Back": "artificial,manmade,human work,human skill,artificiality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "深刻", "Back": "serious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "診察", "Back": "medical examination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人種", "Back": "race (of people)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "信じる", "Back": "to believe,to place trust in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人生", "Back": "(human) life (i.e. conception to death)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "親戚", "Back": "relative", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "新鮮", "Back": "fresh", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "心臓", "Back": "heart", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "身体", "Back": "the body", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "身長", "Back": "height (of body),stature", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "慎重", "Back": "discretion,prudence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "心配", "Back": "worry,concern,anxiety,care", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "審判", "Back": "refereeing,trial,judgement,umpire,referee", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人物", "Back": "character,personality,person,man,personage,talented man", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "進歩", "Back": "progress,development", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "親友", "Back": "close friend,buddy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "信用", "Back": "confidence,dependence,credit,faith", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "信頼", "Back": "reliance,trust,confidence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "心理", "Back": "mentality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人類", "Back": "mankind,humanity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "巣", "Back": "nest,rookery,breeding place,beehive,cobweb", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "図", "Back": "figure (e.g. Fig 1),drawing,picture,illustration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "水準", "Back": "(1) water level,(2) level,standard", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "推薦", "Back": "recommendation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スイッチ", "Back": "switch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "随分", "Back": "extremely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "睡眠", "Back": "sleep", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "数字", "Back": "numeral,figure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スープ", "Back": "(Western) soup", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "末", "Back": "the end of,powder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "姿", "Back": "figure,shape,appearance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スキー", "Back": "skiing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "空く", "Back": "(1) to open,to become empty,(2) to be less crowded", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "救う", "Back": "to rescue from,to help out of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "優れる", "Back": "to surpass,to outstrip,to excel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スケート", "Back": "skate(s),skating", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "すごい", "Back": "terrible,dreadful,terrific,amazing,great", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "少しも", "Back": "anything of,not one bit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "過ごす", "Back": "to pass,to spend,to go through,to tide over", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "筋", "Back": "muscle,string,line", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "進める", "Back": "to advance,to promote,to hasten", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勧める", "Back": "to recommend,to advise,to encourage,to offer (wine)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スター", "Back": "star", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スタイル", "Back": "style", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スタンド", "Back": "stand", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "頭痛", "Back": "headache", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ずっと", "Back": "consecutively,throughout,a lot", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "すてき", "Back": "lovely,dreamy,beautiful,great", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "既に", "Back": "already,too late", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "すなわち", "Back": "that is,namely,i.e.", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "素晴らしい", "Back": "wonderful,splendid,magnificent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スピーチ", "Back": "speech", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "全て", "Back": "all,the whole,entirely,in general,wholly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "済ませる", "Back": "to be finished", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "角", "Back": "horn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "すみません", "Back": "sorry,excuse me", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "為る", "Back": "to change,to be of use,to reach to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "すると", "Back": "thereupon,hereupon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鋭い", "Back": "pointed,sharp", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "背", "Back": "height,stature", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "正", "Back": "(logical) true,regular", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生", "Back": "(1) draft (beer),(2) raw,unprocessed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "性", "Back": "sex,gender", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "所為", "Back": "cause,reason,fault", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "税", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "性格", "Back": "character,personality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "正確", "Back": "accurate,punctuality,exactness,authenticity,veracity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "世紀", "Back": "century,era", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "請求", "Back": "claim,demand,application,request", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "税金", "Back": "tax,duty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "清潔", "Back": "clean", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "制限", "Back": "restriction,restraint,limitation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "成功", "Back": "success,hit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生産", "Back": "production,manufacture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "正式", "Back": "due form,official,formality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "精神", "Back": "mind,soul,heart,spirit,intention", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "成人", "Back": "adult", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "精々", "Back": "at the most,at best,to the utmost,as much (far) as possible", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "成績", "Back": "results,record", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "製造", "Back": "manufacture,production", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "贅沢", "Back": "luxury,extravagance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "成長", "Back": "growth,grow to adulthood", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "制度", "Back": "system,institution,organization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "青年", "Back": "youth,young man", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "製品", "Back": "manufactured goods,finished goods", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "政府", "Back": "government,administration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生物", "Back": "raw food", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生命", "Back": "life,existence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "整理", "Back": "sorting,arrangement,adjustment,regulation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "咳", "Back": "cough", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "石炭", "Back": "coal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "責任", "Back": "duty,responsibility", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "石油", "Back": "oil,petroleum,kerosene", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "世間", "Back": "world,society", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "説", "Back": "theory", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "積極的", "Back": "positive,active,proactive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "設計", "Back": "plan,design", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "絶対", "Back": "absolute,unconditional,absoluteness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "セット", "Back": "set", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "設備", "Back": "equipment,device,facilities,installation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "絶滅", "Back": "destruction,extinction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "節約", "Back": "economising,saving", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "是非", "Back": "certainly,without fail", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "責める", "Back": "to condemn,to blame,to criticize", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "世話", "Back": "looking after,help,aid,assistance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "善", "Back": "good,goodness,right,virtue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "全", "Back": "all,whole,entire,complete,overall,pan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "全員", "Back": "all members (unanimity),all hands,the whole crew", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "専攻", "Back": "major subject,special study", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "全国", "Back": "country-wide,nation-wide,whole country,national", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "先日", "Back": "the other day,a few days ago", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "前者", "Back": "the former", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "選手", "Back": "(1) player (in game),(2) team", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "前進", "Back": "advance,drive,progress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "全然", "Back": "(1) wholly,entirely,completely,(2) not at all (with neg. verb)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "センター", "Back": "a center", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "全体", "Back": "whole,entirety,whatever (is the matter)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "選択", "Back": "selection,choice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "そう", "Back": "so", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "象", "Back": "elephant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "騒音", "Back": "noise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "増加", "Back": "increase,addition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "操作", "Back": "operation,management,processing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "掃除", "Back": "cleaning,sweeping", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "想像", "Back": "imagination,guess", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "相続", "Back": "succession,inheritance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "相談", "Back": "consultation,discussion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "装置", "Back": "equipment,installation,apparatus", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "相当", "Back": "suitable,fair,tolerable,proper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "速度", "Back": "speed,velocity,rate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "そこ", "Back": "bottom,sole", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "底", "Back": "bottom,sole", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "そこで", "Back": "so (conj),accordingly,now,then,thereupon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "組織", "Back": "(1) organization,(2) structure,construction,(3) tissue,(4) system", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "そして", "Back": "and", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "注ぐ", "Back": "to pour (into),to irrigate,to pay,to fill,to feed (e.g. a fire)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "育つ", "Back": "to raise (child),to be brought up,to grow (up)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "そっくり", "Back": "all,altogether,entirely,be just like,the splitting image of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "そっと", "Back": "face of the earth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "袖", "Back": "sleeve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "備える", "Back": "to furnish,to provide for,to equip,to install", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "その", "Back": "the,that", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "そのうち", "Back": "eventually,sooner or later,of the previously mentioned", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "そのまま", "Back": "without change,as it is (i.e. now)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "側", "Back": "side,edge,third person", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ソファー", "Back": "sofa,couch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "粗末", "Back": "crude,rough,plain,humble", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "それ", "Back": "it,that", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "それぞれ", "Back": "each,every,either,respectively,severally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "それでも", "Back": "but (still),and yet,nevertheless,even so,notwithstanding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "それと", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "それとも", "Back": "or,or else", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "損", "Back": "loss,disadvantage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "損害", "Back": "damage,injury,loss", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "尊敬", "Back": "respect,esteem,reverence,honour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "存在", "Back": "existence,being", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "尊重", "Back": "respect,esteem,regard", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "田", "Back": "rice field", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "他", "Back": "other (esp. places and things)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "対", "Back": "pair,couple,set", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "台", "Back": "stand,rack,table,support", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "題", "Back": "title,subject,theme,topic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "体育", "Back": "physical education,gymnastics,athletics", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "体温", "Back": "temperature (body)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大会", "Back": "convention,tournament,mass meeting,rally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大気", "Back": "atmosphere", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "代金", "Back": "price,payment,cost,charge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "退屈", "Back": "tedium,boredom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "滞在", "Back": "stay,sojourn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大使", "Back": "ambassador", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大した", "Back": "considerable,great,important,significant,a big deal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "対象", "Back": "target,object (of worship, study, etc),subject (of taxation, etc)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大臣", "Back": "cabinet minister", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "対する", "Back": "to face,to confront,to oppose", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大戦", "Back": "great war,great battle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大抵", "Back": "usually,generally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "態度", "Back": "attitude,manner", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大統領", "Back": "president,chief executive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大半", "Back": "majority,mostly,generally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "代表", "Back": "representative,representation,delegation,type,example,model", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大部分", "Back": "most part,greater part,majority", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "タイプライター", "Back": "typewriter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大変", "Back": "awful,dreadful,terrible,very", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "逮捕", "Back": "arrest,apprehension,capture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ダイヤ", "Back": "(1) dyer,(2) diagram,(3) (railway) schedule,(4) diamond", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "太陽", "Back": "sun,solar", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "平ら", "Back": "flatness,level,smooth,calm,plain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "代理", "Back": "representation,agency,proxy,deputy,agent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大陸", "Back": "continent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "倒す", "Back": "to throw down,to beat,to bring down,to blow down", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "タオル", "Back": "(hand) towel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "だが", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "互い", "Back": "mutual,reciprocal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宝", "Back": "treasure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "だから", "Back": "so,therefore", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宅", "Back": "house,home,husband", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "だけど", "Back": "however", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "確かめる", "Back": "to ascertain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "多少", "Back": "more or less,somewhat,a little,some", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "助ける", "Back": "to help,to save,to rescue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ただ", "Back": "free of charge,mere,only", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "唯", "Back": "free of charge,mere,sole,only,usual,common", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "戦い", "Back": "battle,fight,struggle,conflict", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "戦う", "Back": "to fight,to battle,to combat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "叩く", "Back": "to strike,to clap,to dust,to beat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "直ちに", "Back": "at once,immediately,directly,in person", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "立ち上がる", "Back": "to stand up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "立場", "Back": "standpoint,position,situation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "経つ", "Back": "to pass,to lapse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "達する", "Back": "to reach,to get to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "だって", "Back": "but,because,even,also,too", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "たっぷり", "Back": "full,in plenty,ample", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "縦", "Back": "length,height", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "たとえ", "Back": "simile,metaphor,allegory", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "谷", "Back": "valley", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "他人", "Back": "another person,unrelated person,outsider,stranger", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "種", "Back": "(1) seed,(2) material,(3) cause,source", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "束", "Back": "handbreadth,bundle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "度", "Back": "counter for occurrences", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "旅", "Back": "travel,trip,journey", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "たびたび", "Back": "often,repeatedly,frequently", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "多分", "Back": "perhaps,probably", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "玉", "Back": "ball,sphere,coin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弾", "Back": "bullet,shot,shell", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "偶", "Back": "even number,couple,man and wife,friend", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "偶々", "Back": "casually,unexpectedly,accidentally,by chance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "たまらない", "Back": "intolerable,unbearable,unendurable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "黙る", "Back": "to be silent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "駄目", "Back": "useless,no good,hopeless", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "試し", "Back": "trial,test", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "試す", "Back": "to attempt,to test", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "便り", "Back": "news,tidings,information,correspondence,letter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "頼る", "Back": "to rely on,to have recourse to,to depend on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "段", "Back": "step,stair,flight of steps,grade,rank,level", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誰か", "Back": "someone,somebody", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "単位", "Back": "unit,denomination,credit (in school)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "単語", "Back": "word,vocabulary,(usually) single-character word", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "男子", "Back": "youth,young man", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "単純", "Back": "simplicity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誕生", "Back": "birth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ダンス", "Back": "dance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "団体", "Back": "organization,association", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "担当", "Back": "(in) charge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "単なる", "Back": "mere,simple,sheer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "単に", "Back": "simply,merely,only,solely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地", "Back": "earth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地位", "Back": "(social) position,status", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地域", "Back": "area,region", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "チーズ", "Back": "cheese", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "チーム", "Back": "team", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "知恵", "Back": "wisdom,wit,sagacity,sense,intelligence,advice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地下", "Back": "basement,underground", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "違い", "Back": "difference,discrepancy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "違いない", "Back": "(phrase) sure,no mistaking it,for certain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "近頃", "Back": "lately,recently,nowadays", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地球", "Back": "the earth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地区", "Back": "district,section,sector", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遅刻", "Back": "lateness,late coming", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "知事", "Back": "prefectural governor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "知識", "Back": "knowledge,information", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "父親", "Back": "father", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "知能", "Back": "intelligence,brains", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地平線", "Back": "horizon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地方", "Back": "area,locality,district,region,the coast", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "茶", "Back": "tea", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "チャンス", "Back": "chance,opportunity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ちゃんと", "Back": "perfectly,properly,exactly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中", "Back": "inside,middle,among", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "注", "Back": "annotation,explanatory note", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中央", "Back": "centre,central,center,middle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中学", "Back": "middle school,junior high school", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中古", "Back": "(1) used,second-hand,old", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中止", "Back": "suspension,stoppage,discontinuance,interruption", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "駐車", "Back": "parking (e.g. car)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "昼食", "Back": "lunch,midday meal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中心", "Back": "center,core,heart,pivot,emphasis,balance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "注目", "Back": "notice,attention,observation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "注文", "Back": "order,request", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "長期", "Back": "long time period", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "調査", "Back": "investigation,examination,inquiry,survey", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "調子", "Back": "tune,tone,key", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "頂上", "Back": "top,summit,peak", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ちょうだい", "Back": "(1) please do for me (preceded by -te),(2) reception,being given,get", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貯金", "Back": "(bank) savings", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "直接", "Back": "direct,immediate,personal,firsthand", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "著者", "Back": "author,writer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遂に", "Back": "finally,at last", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通過", "Back": "passage through,passing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通学", "Back": "commuting to school", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通行", "Back": "passage,passing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通じる", "Back": "to run to,to lead to,to communicate,to understand", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通信", "Back": "correspondence,communication,news,signal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捕まる", "Back": "to be caught,to be arrested", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "掴む", "Back": "to seize,to catch,to grasp", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "疲れ", "Back": "tiredness,fatigue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "月", "Back": "moon,month", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "付き合い", "Back": "association,socializing,fellowship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "次々", "Back": "in succession,one by one", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "就く", "Back": "to settle in (place),to take (seat, position),to study (under teacher)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "付ける", "Back": "to attach,to join,to add,to append", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "土", "Back": "earth,soil", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "続き", "Back": "sequel,continuation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "包み", "Back": "bundle,package,parcel,bale", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勤め", "Back": "(1) service,duty,business,responsibility,task,(2) Buddhist religious services", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "務め", "Back": "(1) service,duty,(2) Buddhist religious services", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "繋ぐ", "Back": "to tie,to fasten,to connect,to transfer (phone call)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "常に", "Back": "always,constantly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "翼", "Back": "wings", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "つまり", "Back": "in short,in brief,in other words", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "罪", "Back": "crime,fault,indiscretion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "詰める", "Back": "to pack,to shorten,to work out (details)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "積もる", "Back": "to pile up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "梅雨", "Back": "rainy season,rain during the rainy season", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "辛い", "Back": "painful,heart-breaking", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "釣", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "連れ", "Back": "companion,company", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "で", "Back": "outflow,coming (going) out,graduate (of)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出会い", "Back": "meeting,rendezvous,encounter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出会う", "Back": "to meet by chance,to come across,to happen to encounter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "提案", "Back": "proposal,proposition,suggestion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "定期", "Back": "fixed term", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "抵抗", "Back": "electrical resistance,resistance,opposition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "提出", "Back": "presentation,submission,filing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "程度", "Back": "degree,amount,grade,standard,of the order of (following a number)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "停留所", "Back": "bus or tram stop", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "デート", "Back": "date,go on a date", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "敵", "Back": "enemy,rival", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出来事", "Back": "incident,affair,happening,event", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "適する", "Back": "to fit,to suit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "適切", "Back": "pertinent,appropriate,adequate,relevance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "適度", "Back": "moderate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "適用", "Back": "applying", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "できる", "Back": "to be able to,to be ready,to occur", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出来るだけ", "Back": "if at all possible", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "できれば", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手品", "Back": "sleight of hand,conjuring trick,magic,juggling", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ですから", "Back": "therefore", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鉄", "Back": "iron", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "哲学", "Back": "philosophy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手伝い", "Back": "help,helper,assistant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "徹底", "Back": "thoroughness,completeness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鉄道", "Back": "railroad", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "徹夜", "Back": "all night,all night vigil,sleepless night", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "では", "Back": "chance of going out,opportunity (to succeed),moment of departure,beginning of work", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手間", "Back": "time,labour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "でも", "Back": "but,however", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "デモ", "Back": "(abbr) demo,demonstration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "典型", "Back": "type,pattern,archetypal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "天候", "Back": "weather", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "電子", "Back": "electron", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "テント", "Back": "tent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "伝統", "Back": "tradition,convention", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "天然", "Back": "nature,spontaneity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "問い", "Back": "question,query", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "党", "Back": "party (political)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "塔", "Back": "tower,pagoda", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "どう", "Back": "child,servant,foolishness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "答案", "Back": "examination paper,examination script", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同一", "Back": "identity,sameness,similarity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "どうか", "Back": "copper coin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "当時", "Back": "at that time,in those days", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "動詞", "Back": "verb", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同時", "Back": "simultaneous(ly),concurrent,same time,synchronous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "どうしても", "Back": "by all means,at any cost,no matter what", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "到着", "Back": "arrival", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "道徳", "Back": "morals", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "投票", "Back": "voting,poll", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同様", "Back": "identical,equal to,same (kind),like", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同僚", "Back": "coworker,colleague,associate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "道路", "Back": "road,highway", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通す", "Back": "to let pass,to overlook,to continue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通り", "Back": "in accordance with ~,following ~,~ Street,~ Avenue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通り過ぎる", "Back": "to pass,to pass through", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "都会", "Back": "city", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "時", "Back": "(1) time,hour,(2) occasion,moment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "解く", "Back": "to unfasten", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "毒", "Back": "poison,toxicant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "得意", "Back": "pride,triumph,prosperity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "読書", "Back": "reading", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "独身", "Back": "bachelorhood,single,unmarried,celibate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "特徴", "Back": "feature,characteristic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "独特", "Back": "peculiarity,uniqueness,characteristic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "独立", "Back": "independence (e.g. Ind. Day),self-support", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "解ける", "Back": "to come untied,to come apart", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "どこか", "Back": "somewhere,anywhere", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ところが", "Back": "however,while,even if", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ところで", "Back": "by the way,even if,no matter what", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "登山", "Back": "mountain-climbing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "都市", "Back": "town,city,municipal,urban", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "年月", "Back": "months and years", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "図書", "Back": "books", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "年寄", "Back": "old people,the aged", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "閉じる", "Back": "to close (e.g. book, eyes),to shut", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "途端", "Back": "just (now, at the moment, etc.)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "土地", "Back": "plot of land,lot,soil", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "突然", "Back": "abruptly,suddenly,unexpectedly,all at once", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "トップ", "Back": "top", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "届く", "Back": "to reach", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "とにかく", "Back": "anyhow,at any rate,anyway,somehow or other,generally speaking,in any case", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "飛ばす", "Back": "to skip over,to omit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "飛び出す", "Back": "to jump out,to rush out,to fly out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "留める", "Back": "to fasten,to turn off,to detain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "友", "Back": "friend,companion,pal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "共に", "Back": "sharing with,participate in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "土曜", "Back": "Saturday", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "虎", "Back": "tiger", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ドライブ", "Back": "drive,trip by car,driving", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "トラック", "Back": "(1) truck,(2) (running) track", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ドラマ", "Back": "drama", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "トランプ", "Back": "playing cards (lit: trump)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り上げる", "Back": "to take up,to pick up,to disqualify,to confiscate,to deprive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "努力", "Back": "great effort,exertion,endeavour,effort", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "どれ", "Back": "well,now,let me see,which (of three or more)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ドレス", "Back": "dress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取れる", "Back": "to come off,to be taken off,to be removed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "泥", "Back": "mud", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "とん", "Back": "ton", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "とんでもない", "Back": "unexpected,offensive,What a thing to say!,No way!", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "どんな", "Back": "what,what kind of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "どんなに", "Back": "how,how much", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "トンネル", "Back": "tunnel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "名", "Back": "name,reputation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "内容", "Back": "subject,contents,matter,substance,detail,import", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "なお", "Back": "straight,mischief,ordinary,common", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仲", "Back": "relation,relationship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "流す", "Back": "to drain,to float,to shed (blood, tears),to cruise (e.g. taxi)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "なかなか", "Back": "very,considerably,easily", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "半ば", "Back": "middle,half,semi,halfway,partly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仲間", "Back": "company,fellow,colleague,associate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "眺め", "Back": "scene,view,prospect,outlook", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "眺める", "Back": "to view,to gaze at", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "流れ", "Back": "stream,current", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "流れる", "Back": "to stream,to flow,to run (ink),to be washed away", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無し", "Back": "without", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "なぜなら", "Back": "because", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "謎", "Back": "riddle,puzzle,enigma", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "納得", "Back": "consent,assent,understanding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "等", "Back": "et cetera,etc.,and the like", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何", "Back": "what", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何か", "Back": "something", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "なにも", "Back": "nothing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鍋", "Back": "saucepan,pot", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "怠ける", "Back": "to be idle,to neglect", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "波", "Back": "wave", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "涙", "Back": "tear", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悩む", "Back": "to be worried,to be troubled", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "成る", "Back": "to become", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "縄", "Back": "rope,hemp", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何で", "Back": "Why?,What for?", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何でも", "Back": "by all means,everything", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何とか", "Back": "somehow,anyhow,one way or another", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "似合う", "Back": "to suit,to match,to become,to be like", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "匂い", "Back": "odour,scent,smell,stench", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "苦手", "Back": "poor (at),weak (in),dislike (of)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "握る", "Back": "to grasp,to seize,to mould sushi", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日", "Back": "sun,sunshine,day", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日常", "Back": "ordinary,regular,everyday,usual", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日曜", "Back": "Sunday", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日光", "Back": "sunlight", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日中", "Back": "daytime,broad daylight", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "にっこり", "Back": "smile sweetly,smile,grin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日本", "Back": "Japan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "入院", "Back": "hospitalization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "入学", "Back": "entry to school or university,matriculation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "入場", "Back": "entrance,admission,entering", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人気", "Back": "sign of life", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人間", "Back": "human being,man,person", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "抜く", "Back": "to extract,to omit,to surpass,to draw out,to unplug", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "抜ける", "Back": "to come out,to fall out,to be omitted", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "布", "Back": "cloth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "濡れる", "Back": "to get wet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ね", "Back": "value,price,cost,worth,merit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "根", "Back": "root", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "値", "Back": "value,price,cost", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "願い", "Back": "desire,wish,request", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "願う", "Back": "to desire,to wish,to request", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鼠", "Back": "(1) mouse,rat,(2) dark gray,slate color", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "値段", "Back": "price,cost", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "熱心", "Back": "zeal,enthusiasm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "熱帯", "Back": "tropics", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "熱中", "Back": "nuts!,enthusiasm,zeal,mania", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "年間", "Back": "year", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "年中", "Back": "whole year,always,everyday", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "年代", "Back": "age,era,period,date", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "年齢", "Back": "age,years", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "野", "Back": "field", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "能", "Back": "being skilled in,nicely,properly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "農家", "Back": "farmer,farm family", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "農業", "Back": "agriculture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "農民", "Back": "farmers,peasants", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "能力", "Back": "ability,faculty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ノー", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "残す", "Back": "to leave (behind, over),to bequeath,to save,to reserve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "残り", "Back": "remnant,residue,remaining,left-over", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乗せる", "Back": "to place on (something),to take on board,to give a ride", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "除く", "Back": "to remove,to exclude,to except", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "望み", "Back": "wish,desire,(a) hope", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "望む", "Back": "to desire,to wish for,to see,to command (a view of)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ノック", "Back": "(1) knock,(2) fungo (baseball)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "喉", "Back": "throat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "伸ばす", "Back": "to lengthen,to stretch,to reach out,to grow (beard)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "伸びる", "Back": "to stretch,to extend,to make progress,to grow (beard, body height)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "述べる", "Back": "to state,to express,to mention", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "昇る", "Back": "to arise,to ascend,to go up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "のんびり", "Back": "carefree,at leisure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "場", "Back": "place,field (physics)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "はあ", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "パーセント", "Back": "percent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "はい", "Back": "wear,put on (sword)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "灰", "Back": "ash", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "バイオリン", "Back": "violin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ハイキング", "Back": "hiking", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "配達", "Back": "delivery,distribution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "パイプ", "Back": "(1) pipe,tube,(2) channels, official or otherwise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "俳優", "Back": "actor,actress,player,performer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "パイロット", "Back": "pilot", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "墓", "Back": "grave,tomb", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "馬鹿", "Back": "fool,idiot,trivial matter,folly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "博士", "Back": "doctorate,PhD", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "計る", "Back": "to measure,to weigh,to survey", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "履く", "Back": "to wear,to put on (lower body)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "吐く", "Back": "(1) to breathe,(2) to tell (lies),(3) to vomit,to disgorge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "拍手", "Back": "clapping hands,applause", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "莫大", "Back": "enormous,vast", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "爆発", "Back": "explosion,detonation,eruption", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "博物館", "Back": "museum", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "激しい", "Back": "violent,vehement,intense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "はさみ", "Back": "scissors", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "破産", "Back": "(personal) bankruptcy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "端", "Back": "end (e.g. of street),edge,tip,margin,point", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "始まり", "Back": "origin,beginning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "パス", "Back": "path,pass (in games)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "外す", "Back": "to unfasten,to remove", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "パスポート", "Back": "passport", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "旗", "Back": "flag", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "肌", "Back": "skin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "裸", "Back": "naked,nude", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "畑", "Back": "field", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "二十", "Back": "20 years old,20th year", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "働き", "Back": "work,labor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "バッグ", "Back": "bag,bug", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発見", "Back": "discovery,detection,finding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発行", "Back": "issue (publications)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発車", "Back": "departure of a vehicle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "罰する", "Back": "to punish,to penalize", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発達", "Back": "development,growth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ばったり", "Back": "with a clash (thud),with a bang,plump,flop", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発展", "Back": "development,growth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発表", "Back": "announcement,publication", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発明", "Back": "invention", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "話し合う", "Back": "to discuss,to talk together", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "離す", "Back": "to part,divide,separate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "放す", "Back": "to separate,to set free", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "離れる", "Back": "to be separated from,to leave,to go away,to be a long way off", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "羽", "Back": "counter for birds,counter for rabbits", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幅", "Back": "width,breadth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "母親", "Back": "mother", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "省く", "Back": "to omit,to eliminate,to curtail,to economize", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "場面", "Back": "scene,setting (e.g. of novel)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "腹", "Back": "abdomen,belly,stomach", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原", "Back": "field,plain,prairie,tundra,moor,wilderness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "針", "Back": "needle,hand (e.g. clock)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "張る", "Back": "to stick,to paste", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "番", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "バン", "Back": "bun,van (caravan),VAN (value-added network)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "範囲", "Back": "extent,scope,sphere,range", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "反抗", "Back": "opposition,resistance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "犯罪", "Back": "crime", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ハンサム", "Back": "handsome", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "判断", "Back": "judgement,decision", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "犯人", "Back": "offender,criminal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "販売", "Back": "sale,selling,marketing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "灯", "Back": "light", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ビール", "Back": "beer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "被害", "Back": "damage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "比較", "Back": "comparison", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "轢く", "Back": "to run somebody over (with vehicle),to knock someone down", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ピクニック", "Back": "picnic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悲劇", "Back": "tragedy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "飛行", "Back": "aviation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "膝", "Back": "knee,lap", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "非常", "Back": "emergency,extraordinary,unusual", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "美人", "Back": "beautiful person (woman)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "びっくり", "Back": "be surprised,be amazed,be frightened,astonishment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日付", "Back": "date,dating", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "必死", "Back": "inevitable death,desperation,frantic,inevitable result", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぴったり", "Back": "exactly,neatly,sharp", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引っ張る", "Back": "(1) to pull,to draw,to stretch,to drag,(2) to pull the ball (baseball)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "否定", "Back": "negation,denial,repudiation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ビデオ", "Back": "video", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一言", "Back": "single word", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人込み", "Back": "crowd of people", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "等しい", "Back": "equal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "独り", "Back": "alone,unmarried", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一人一人", "Back": "one by one,each,one at a time", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "批判", "Back": "criticism,judgement,comment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "批評", "Back": "criticism,review,commentary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "秘密", "Back": "secret,secrecy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "微妙", "Back": "delicate,subtle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "紐", "Back": "(1) string,cord,(2) pimp", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "費用", "Back": "cost,expense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "表", "Back": "table (e.g. Tab 1),chart,list", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "秒", "Back": "second (60th min)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "評価", "Back": "valuation,estimation,assessment,evaluation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "表現", "Back": "expression,presentation,representation (math)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "表情", "Back": "facial expression", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "平等", "Back": "equality (a),impartiality,evenness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "評判", "Back": "fame,reputation,popularity,arrant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "表面", "Back": "surface,outside,face,appearance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "広がる", "Back": "to spread (out),to extend,to stretch,to reach to,to get around", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "瓶", "Back": "bottle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "便", "Back": "way,means", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ピン", "Back": "pin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不", "Back": "un,non,negative prefix", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無", "Back": "nothing,naught,nil,zero", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分", "Back": "dividing,part", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不安", "Back": "anxiety,uneasiness,insecurity,suspense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "風景", "Back": "scenery", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夫婦", "Back": "married couple,husband and wife", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "笛", "Back": "flute,pipe", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不可", "Back": "wrong,bad,improper,unjustifiable,inadvisable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "武器", "Back": "weapon,arms,ordinance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "服装", "Back": "garments", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "含む", "Back": "to hold in the mouth,to bear in mind", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "袋", "Back": "bag,sack", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不幸", "Back": "unhappiness,sorrow,misfortune,disaster,accident,death", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "節", "Back": "tune,tone,knot,knob,point", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無事", "Back": "safety,peace,quietness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不思議", "Back": "mystery,curiosity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不自由", "Back": "discomfort,disability,inconvenience,destitution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夫人", "Back": "wife,Mrs,madam", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "婦人", "Back": "woman,female", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不正", "Back": "injustice,unfairness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "防ぐ", "Back": "to defend (against),to protect,to prevent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不足", "Back": "insufficiency,shortage,deficiency,lack,dearth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "舞台", "Back": "stage (theatre)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "双子", "Back": "twins,a twin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "再び", "Back": "again,once more,a second time", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "普段", "Back": "usually,habitually,ordinarily,always", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "縁", "Back": "a means, e.g. of living", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "打つ", "Back": "to hit,to strike", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物価", "Back": "prices of commodities,prices (in general)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物質", "Back": "material,substance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物理", "Back": "physics", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "筆", "Back": "writing brush", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ふと", "Back": "suddenly,casually,accidentally,incidentally,unexpectedly,unintentionally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "船", "Back": "ship,boat,watercraft,shipping,vessel,steamship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "部分", "Back": "portion,section,part", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不平", "Back": "complaint,discontent,dissatisfaction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不満", "Back": "dissatisfaction,displeasure,discontent,complaints,unhappiness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "プラス", "Back": "plus", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "プラン", "Back": "plan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不利", "Back": "disadvantage,handicap,unfavorable,drawback", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "振る", "Back": "(1) to wave,to shake,to swing,(2) to sprinkle,(3) to cast (actor),to allocate (work)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "震える", "Back": "to shiver,to shake,to quake", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ブレーキ", "Back": "a brake", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "触れる", "Back": "to touch,to be touched,to touch on a subject,to feel,to violate (law, copyright, etc.),to perceive,t", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "風呂", "Back": "bath", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "プロ", "Back": "professional", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "文", "Back": "sentence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雰囲気", "Back": "atmosphere (e.g. musical),mood,ambience", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分析", "Back": "analysis", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "文明", "Back": "civilization,culture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分野", "Back": "field,sphere,realm,division,branch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "塀", "Back": "wall,fence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "平均", "Back": "equilibrium,balance,average,mean", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "平和", "Back": "peace,harmony", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "別に", "Back": "(not) particularly,nothing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "減らす", "Back": "to abate,to decrease,to diminish,to shorten", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "減る", "Back": "to decrease (in size or number),to diminish,to abate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ベルト", "Back": "Belt for western clothes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "変化", "Back": "goblin,ghost,apparition,bugbear", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ペンキ", "Back": "(n) paint (nl: pek)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勉強", "Back": "study,diligence,discount,reduction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "変更", "Back": "change,modification,alteration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ベンチ", "Back": "bench", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弁当", "Back": "box lunch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "方", "Back": "side", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "法", "Back": "Act (law: the X Act)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "棒", "Back": "pole,rod,stick", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "冒険", "Back": "risk,venture,adventure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "方向", "Back": "direction,course,way", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "報告", "Back": "report,information", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宝石", "Back": "gem,jewel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "放送", "Back": "broadcast,broadcasting", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "豊富", "Back": "abundance,wealth,plenty,bounty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "方法", "Back": "method,manner,way,means,technique", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "訪問", "Back": "call,visit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "吠える", "Back": "to bark,to bay,to howl,to bellow,to roar,to cry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ボーイ", "Back": "boy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ボート", "Back": "rowing boat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ホーム", "Back": "(1) platform,(2) home", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ボール", "Back": "ball,bowl", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "外", "Back": "other place,the rest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誇り", "Back": "pride", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "埃", "Back": "dust", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "保証", "Back": "guarantee,security,assurance,pledge,warranty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "保存", "Back": "preservation,conservation,storage,maintenance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "程", "Back": "degree,extent,bounds,limit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "歩道", "Back": "footpath,walkway,sidewalk", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仏", "Back": "Buddha,merciful person,Buddhist image,the dead", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "骨", "Back": "bone", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "炎", "Back": "flame", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "頬", "Back": "cheek (of face)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ほぼ", "Back": "almost,roughly,approximately", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "微笑む", "Back": "to smile", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "褒める", "Back": "to praise,to admire,to speak well", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "濠", "Back": "moat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "本当", "Back": "truth,reality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "本人", "Back": "the person himself", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "本物", "Back": "genuine article", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぼんやり", "Back": "absent-minded,block-head,dim,faint,vague", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "間", "Back": "space,room,time,pause", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "まあ", "Back": "(female) you might say", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "マーケット", "Back": "market", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "マイク", "Back": "mike", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "迷子", "Back": "lost (stray) child", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "任せる", "Back": "to entrust to another,to leave to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幕", "Back": "curtain,bunting,act (in play)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "負け", "Back": "defeat,loss,losing (a game)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "孫", "Back": "grandchild", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "まさか", "Back": "by no means", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "まさに", "Back": "correctly,surely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真面目", "Back": "diligent,serious,honest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "増す", "Back": "to increase,to grow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "先ず", "Back": "first (of all),to start with,about,almost,hardly (with neg. verb)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貧しい", "Back": "poor,needy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "マスター", "Back": "proprietor,manager,barowner,master (e.g. arts, science)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ますます", "Back": "increasingly,more and more", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "又", "Back": "again,and", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "未だ", "Back": "yet,still,more,besides", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "街", "Back": "(1) town,(2) street,road", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "間違い", "Back": "mistake", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "松", "Back": "(1) pine tree,(2) highest (of a three-tier ranking system)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真っ赤", "Back": "deep red,flushed (of face)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真っ直ぐ", "Back": "straight (ahead),direct,upright", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "全く", "Back": "really,truly,entirely,completely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "祭", "Back": "festival,feast", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "学ぶ", "Back": "to study (in depth),to learn,to take lessons in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真似", "Back": "mimicry,imitation,behavior,pretense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "招く", "Back": "to invite", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ママ", "Back": "Mama", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "豆", "Back": "beans,peas", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "守る", "Back": "to protect,to obey,to guard,to abide (by the rules)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "丸", "Back": "circle,full (month),perfection,purity,suffix for ship names", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "丸い", "Back": "round,circular,spherical", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "まるで", "Back": "quite,entirely,completely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "回す", "Back": "to turn,to revolve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "回り", "Back": "circumference,surroundings,circulation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "万一", "Back": "by some chance,by some possibility,if by any chance,10E4:1 odds", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "満足", "Back": "satisfaction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "身", "Back": "body,main part,oneself,sword", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実", "Back": "fruit,nut,seed,content,good result", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見送り", "Back": "seeing one off,farewell,escort", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "味方", "Back": "friend,ally,supporter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見事", "Back": "splendid,magnificent,beautiful,admirable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ミス", "Back": "miss (mistake, error, failure),Miss", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "満ちる", "Back": "to be full,to rise (tide),to mature,to expire", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "密", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "認める", "Back": "to recognize,to appreciate,to approve,to admit,to notice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "皆", "Back": "all,everyone,everybody", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見舞い", "Back": "enquiry,expression of sympathy,expression of concern", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "土産", "Back": "present,souvenir", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "都", "Back": "capital", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "妙", "Back": "strange,unusual", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "明後日", "Back": "day after tomorrow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "未来", "Back": "future (life, tense)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "魅力", "Back": "charm,fascination,glamour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見る", "Back": "to see,to watch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ミルク", "Back": "milk", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "向かい", "Back": "facing,opposite,across the street,other side", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "迎え", "Back": "meeting,person sent to pick up an arrival", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "向く", "Back": "to face", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "向ける", "Back": "to turn towards,to point", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無視", "Back": "disregard,ignore", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "虫歯", "Back": "cavity,tooth decay,decayed tooth,caries", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寧ろ", "Back": "rather,better,instead", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "結ぶ", "Back": "to tie,to bind,to link", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無駄", "Back": "futility,uselessness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夢中", "Back": "daze,(in a) trance,ecstasy,delirium,engrossment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "胸", "Back": "breast,chest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無料", "Back": "free,no charge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "芽", "Back": "sprout", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "明確", "Back": "clear up,clarify,define", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "命じる", "Back": "to order,to command,to appoint", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "名人", "Back": "master,expert", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "命令", "Back": "order,command,decree,directive,(software) instruction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "迷惑", "Back": "trouble,bother,annoyance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "飯", "Back": "(sl) meals,food", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "滅多に", "Back": "rarely (with neg. verb),seldom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "メモ", "Back": "memorandum", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "面", "Back": "face,mug,surface,facial features,mask,face guard,side or facet,corner,page", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "綿", "Back": "cotton,padding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "免許", "Back": "license,permit,licence,certificate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "面倒", "Back": "trouble,difficulty,care,attention", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "メンバー", "Back": "member", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "申し込む", "Back": "to apply for,to make an application", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "申し訳", "Back": "apology,excuse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "毛布", "Back": "blanket", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "燃える", "Back": "to burn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目的", "Back": "purpose,goal,aim,objective,intention", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目標", "Back": "mark,objective,target", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "木曜", "Back": "Thursday", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "文字", "Back": "letter (of alphabet),character", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "もしも", "Back": "if", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "持ち上げる", "Back": "to raise,to lift up,to flatter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "用いる", "Back": "to use,to make use of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勿論", "Back": "of course,certainly,naturally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "最も", "Back": "most,extremely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "尤も", "Back": "quite right,plausible,natural,but then,although", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "元", "Back": "(1) origin,original,(2) former", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "基", "Back": "basis", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "素", "Back": "prime", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "戻す", "Back": "to restore,to put back,to return", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "基づく", "Back": "to be grounded on,to be based on,to be due to,to originate from", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "求める", "Back": "to seek,to request,to demand,to want,to wish for,to search for,to pursue (pleasure),to hunt (a job),", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "者", "Back": "person", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物音", "Back": "sounds", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物語", "Back": "tale,story,legend", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物事", "Back": "things,everything", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "模様", "Back": "pattern,figure,design", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貰う", "Back": "to receive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "文句", "Back": "phrase,complaint", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "やがて", "Back": "before long,soon,at length", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "役", "Back": "use,service,role,position", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "約", "Back": "approximately,about,some", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "訳", "Back": "meaning,reason,circumstances,can be deduced,situation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "役割", "Back": "part,assigning (allotment of) parts,role,duties", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "家賃", "Back": "rent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "厄介", "Back": "trouble,burden,care,bother", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宿", "Back": "inn,lodging", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雇う", "Back": "to employ,to hire", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "屋根", "Back": "roof", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "やはり", "Back": "also,as I thought,still,in spite of,absolutely,of course", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "破る", "Back": "to tear,to violate,to defeat,to smash,to destroy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "辞める", "Back": "to retire", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "やや", "Back": "a little,partially,somewhat,a short time,a while", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "唯一", "Back": "only,sole,unique", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勇気", "Back": "courage,bravery,valour,nerve,boldness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "有効", "Back": "validity,availability,effectiveness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "優秀", "Back": "superiority,excellence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "優勝", "Back": "overall victory,championship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "友情", "Back": "friendship,fellowship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "友人", "Back": "friend", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "有能", "Back": "able,capable,efficient,skill", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "郵便", "Back": "mail,postal service", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夕べ", "Back": "evening", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ユーモア", "Back": "humor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "有利", "Back": "advantageous,better,profitable,lucrative", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "床", "Back": "floor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "愉快", "Back": "pleasant,happy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "輸出", "Back": "export", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "譲る", "Back": "to turn over,to assign,to hand over", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "豊か", "Back": "abundant,wealthy,plentiful,rich", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ゆっくり", "Back": "slowly,at ease", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "輸入", "Back": "importation,import,introduction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "許す", "Back": "to permit,to allow,to approve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夜", "Back": "evening,night", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夜明け", "Back": "dawn,daybreak", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "様", "Back": "way,manner,kind", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "酔う", "Back": "to get drunk,to become intoxicated", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "容易", "Back": "easy,simple,plain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "陽気", "Back": "season,weather,cheerfulness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "要求", "Back": "request,demand,requisition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "用心", "Back": "care,precaution,guarding,caution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "様子", "Back": "aspect,state,appearance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "要するに", "Back": "in a word,after all,the point is ..,in short ..", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "要素", "Back": "element", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "要点", "Back": "gist,main point", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "曜日", "Back": "day of the week", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ヨーロッパ", "Back": "Europe", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "予期", "Back": "expectation,assume will happen,forecast", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "横切る", "Back": "to cross (e.g. arms),to traverse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "予算", "Back": "estimate,budget", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "止す", "Back": "to cease,to abolish,to resign,to give up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "予測", "Back": "prediction,estimation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ヨット", "Back": "yacht", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夜中", "Back": "midnight,dead of night", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "世の中", "Back": "society,the world,the times", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "余分", "Back": "extra,excess,surplus", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "予報", "Back": "forecast,prediction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "予防", "Back": "prevention,precaution,protection against", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "読み", "Back": "reading", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嫁", "Back": "bride,daughter-in-law", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "余裕", "Back": "surplus,composure,margin,room,time,allowance,scope,rope", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "より", "Back": "twist,ply", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "よると", "Back": "according to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "喜び", "Back": "(a) joy,(a) delight,rapture,pleasure,gratification,rejoicing,congratulations,felicitations", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宜しい", "Back": "(hon) good,OK,all right,fine,very well,will do,may,can", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "よろしく", "Back": "well,properly,suitably,best regards,please remember me", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "来", "Back": ",for (10 days),next (year)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ライター", "Back": "lighter,rider,writer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "楽", "Back": "comfort,ease", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ラケット", "Back": "paddle,racket", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "利益", "Back": "profits,gains,(political, economic) interest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "理解", "Back": "understanding,comprehension", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "陸", "Back": "six (used in legal documents)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "利口", "Back": "clever,shrewd,bright,sharp,wise,intelligent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "離婚", "Back": "divorce", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "理想", "Back": "ideal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "率", "Back": "rate,ratio,proportion,percentage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "立派", "Back": "splendid,fine,handsome,elegant,imposing,prominent,legal,legitimate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "留学", "Back": "studying abroad", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "流行", "Back": "fashionable,fad,in vogue,prevailing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "量", "Back": "quantity,amount,volume,portion (of food)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "両替", "Back": "change,money exchange", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "料金", "Back": "fee,charge,fare", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "例", "Back": "instance,example,case", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "礼", "Back": "expression of gratitude", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "礼儀", "Back": "manners,courtesy,etiquette", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "冷静", "Back": "calm,composure,coolness,serenity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "列", "Back": "queue,line,row", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "列車", "Back": "train (ordinary)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "レポート", "Back": "report,paper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "練習", "Back": "practice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "連想", "Back": "association (of ideas),suggestion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "連続", "Back": "serial,consecutive,continuity,continuing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "老人", "Back": "the aged,old person", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "労働", "Back": "manual labor,toil,work", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ロケット", "Back": "locket,rocket", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "論じる", "Back": "to argue,to discuss,to debate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "論争", "Back": "controversy,dispute", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "論文", "Back": "thesis,essay,treatise,paper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "輪", "Back": "ring,hoop,circle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ワイン", "Back": "wine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "わがまま", "Back": "selfishness,egoism,wilfulness,disobedience,whim", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "別れ", "Back": "parting,separation,farewell", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "脇", "Back": "side", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分ける", "Back": "to divide,to separate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "わざと", "Back": "on purpose", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "僅か", "Back": "only,merely,a little,small quantity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "話題", "Back": "topic,subject", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "笑い", "Back": "laugh,laughter,smile", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "割る", "Back": "to divide,to cut,to break,to halve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悪口", "Back": "abuse,insult,slander,evil speaking", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "我々", "Back": "we", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "湾", "Back": "bay,gulf,inlet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{}]
